

Profile

QA Engineer with over 6 years experience in Software Testing. Clear understanding of tasks and ideas in domain area. Motivated to learn, grow in Software Testing. Eager to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail and excellent organizational skills. Excellent reputation for resolving problems, improving customer satisfaction, and driving overall operational improvements.

Employment History

Senior QA at Descartes Kontainers

September 2020 — April 2021

NDA, working on logistic on product software.

Lead QA at Inn4Science, Kharkiv

November 2018 — September 2020

As a Lead QA activities:

- Lead activities with team: mentoring, coordinate.
- The project's realization within pre-estimated time and control of its compliance with technical requirements; Planning in the process of working on a project; work with micro climate inside a team;
- Researched new tools and technologies for potential use by quality assurance team.
- Gathered data on integration issues and vulnerabilities and reported all findings, including improvement recommendations.
- Examination and audit of various cryptocurrency systems: exchanges, trading platforms and wallets.

As a QA activities:

- Preparing and writing automation test scripts for mobile testing with Appium and for web automation testing with Cypress
- · Writing test plans and cases.
- Identified and tracked defects with Jira/Redmine and supported developers in resolving problems by completing additional tests.
- Wrote and optimized test cases to maximize success of manual software testing with consistent, thorough approaches.
- Collaborated with developers and product owners to stay current on product features and intended functionality.
- Analyzed and tested game builds to determine bugs and provide assistance in solving issues.
- Experience with testing APIs in a service oriented architecture (Postman, Swagger)
- Experience with cryptocurrencies and blockchain technology Test design: write test plans, test cases for functional and not functional testing, manuals and acceptance tests.
- Database: PostgreSQL Experience with bug tracking system JIRA, Confluence and Redmine.

Details

Kharkiv/Bratislava, Ukraine/Slovakia, +380935452845 chemgift@gmail.com

Skills

HTML & CSS

JS

Blockchain

Git

Redmine

Jira

Postman

Swagger

Cypress

PostgreSQL

SQL

QA management

Product

development

Quality control

Customer support

Senior Consultant, QA at iTechfinance, Kharkiv

July 2017 — October 2018

- Manual testing desktop finance applications for bank's system (Sophis, Puma).
- Test design: write test cases for functional and not functional testing, manuals Integration and acceptance tests.
- · Database: Oracle, MySQL queries.
- Work with bug tracking system JIRA; Experience with Confluence and Redmine.
- Customer support and consulting for business.
- Wrote, edited and updated project manuals and technical documentation used by quality assurance team.
- Collaborated with developers and product owners to stay current on product features and intended functionality.
- Wrote and optimized test cases to maximize success of manual software testing with consistent, thorough approaches.
- Troubleshoot issues by understanding issue, diagnosing root cause and coming up with effective solutions.
- Identified and tracked defects with Redmine and supported developers in resolving problems by completing additional tests.
- Researched new tools and technologies for potential use by quality assurance team.
- Performed business research and analysis, including financial analysis.

QA at Freelance, Kharkiv

November 2015 — July 2017

- Manual testing: functional and UI for web and mobile applications; API testing Bug tacking system: Jira and Mantis
- Tools: Postman, MySQL
- Wrote and optimized test cases to maximize success of manual software testing with consistent, thorough approaches.
- Wrote, edited and updated project manuals and technical documentation used by quality assurance team.

QA at Scorto, Kharkiv

January 2013 — May 2014

- Manual testing of SOA projects: functional, GUI, security in web and desktop applications.
- Test design: write testcase, manuals and accept tests.
- · Database: write queries in MySQL.
- Work with bug tracking system JIRA.

Test Engeneer at W3, Kharkiv

February 2012 — January 2013

- Collaborated with developers and product owners to stay current on product features and intended functionality.
- Designed and developed automation scripts using open source tools.
- Reviewed requirements, specifications and technical design documents to provide timely and meaningful feedback.
- Conducted regression testing, analyzed results and submitted observations to development team.

- Wrote and optimized test cases to maximize success of manual software testing with consistent, thorough approaches.
- · Designed testing scenarios for usability testing.
- Authored and maintained well-organized, efficient and successful manual test cases for entire team.
- Tracked, prioritized and organized defects with Jira , working with development team to facilitate timely corrections.

Specialist of drug registration and standardisation at Zdorovie Narody, Kharkiv

September 2010 — November 2011

- · Writing specification for substances and drugs.
- · drugs registration and standardisation
- · working with Pharmacopedia
- · writing specification for substances and drugs

Analytical Chemist at LTD Technocom, Kharkiv

June 2010 — September 2010

Kharkiv analysis and quality control of products.

Education

Master, Karazin National University

September 2005 — July 2010

Analytical Chemists, Metrologist